hello I'm Dr manjiri wankar director B
Hospital test you baby center navet pun
today let us discuss one very
interesting question which most of the
patients and their relatives have in
mind does insurance cover IVF treatment
now there have been various uh insurance
companies which have come up with
various models but around 95% of the
insurance companies do not give any
cover for infertility treatments it is
mentioned in the inclusions and
exclusions when you buy the insurance in
the western world as well there are
around two companies which offer an
insurance cover for the IVF the main
reason being that IVF treatment is a
very expensive treatment because most of
the disposables media medicines and
injections are imported from abroad and
hence the cost is too much escalated
apart from this the insurance cover
generally covers surgeries which have a
closure which means that insurance uh
will generally give the cover for heart
ailments or removal of uterus or
cesarian births or deliveries Etc
infertility as we know has a global
success rate of only around 40 to 50%
and there are chances of failure in the
remaining 50% of the women who might
have to do one or two cycles more as
more than expected and hence most of the
insurance companies do not cover IVF so
when whenever you are buying an
insurance policy you can read in the
inclusions and exclusions and in case
there is a company which offers the
infertility treatment you can definitely
go ahead and seek the cover from that
particular company thank you